<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://www.rejniak.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://www.rejniak.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2023-05-09T14:25:02-07:00</updated><id>https://www.rejniak.com/feed.xml</id><title type="html">mick</title><subtitle>Exploring ideas at the intersection of data science and revenue operations &amp; enablement. Also space for personal obervations &amp; rants. </subtitle><entry><title type="html">Revenue Success</title><link href="https://www.rejniak.com/revenue_success/2023/05/08/graduation.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Revenue Success" /><published>2023-05-08T01:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2023-05-08T01:00:00-07:00</updated><id>https://www.rejniak.com/revenue_success/2023/05/08/graduation</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.rejniak.com/revenue_success/2023/05/08/graduation.html"><![CDATA[<p>It is time to start thinking about revenue operations and revenue enablement as a single function. I propose that <em>revenue success</em> is a function akin to <em>customer success</em>. Consider Hubspot’s <a href="https://blog.hubspot.com/service/customer-success">definition of customer success</a>, in part: “Anticipating customer challenges or questions and proactively providing solutions and answers.” Revenue success combines operations and enablement, as a single function, to anticipate challenges of the revenue organization and uses, monitors, modifies, and deploys the information, tools, and processes necessary to successfully address those challenges. Many businesses operate with GTM/sales/revenue operations and enablement as separate functional areas; the ops leader reporting into someone and the enablement leader reporting into someone else. This is a mistake, a holdover from the days of “sales admins” and “sales training.” Separation creates inefficiencies within their respective teams, as well as unnecessary complexity for the field. As both operations and enablement exist to drive revenue growth, they should be woven together to drive a unified, strategic cadence of programs, both novel and routine, to the field.</p>

<p>The implications are huge.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="revenue_success" /><category term="revenue_success" /><category term="sales" /><category term="revenue" /><category term="gtm" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[It is time to start thinking about revenue operations and revenue enablement as a single function. I propose that revenue success is a function akin to customer success. Consider Hubspot’s definition of customer success, in part: “Anticipating customer challenges or questions and proactively providing solutions and answers.” Revenue success combines operations and enablement, as a single function, to anticipate challenges of the revenue organization and uses, monitors, modifies, and deploys the information, tools, and processes necessary to successfully address those challenges. Many businesses operate with GTM/sales/revenue operations and enablement as separate functional areas; the ops leader reporting into someone and the enablement leader reporting into someone else. This is a mistake, a holdover from the days of “sales admins” and “sales training.” Separation creates inefficiencies within their respective teams, as well as unnecessary complexity for the field. As both operations and enablement exist to drive revenue growth, they should be woven together to drive a unified, strategic cadence of programs, both novel and routine, to the field.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Revenue Success</title><link href="https://www.rejniak.com/revenue_success/2023/05/08/revenue_success.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Revenue Success" /><published>2023-05-08T01:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2023-05-08T01:00:00-07:00</updated><id>https://www.rejniak.com/revenue_success/2023/05/08/revenue_success</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.rejniak.com/revenue_success/2023/05/08/revenue_success.html"><![CDATA[<p>It is time to start thinking about revenue operations and revenue enablement as a single function. I propose that <em>revenue success</em> is a function akin to <em>customer success</em>. Hubspot’s <a href="https://blog.hubspot.com/service/customer-success">defines customer success</a>, in part, as a business function that “[anticipates] customer challenges or questions and proactively providing solutions and answers.” Therefore, I suggest a working definition of revenue success:</p>

<dl>
  <dt>Revenue success</dt>
  <dd>Revenue operations and revenue enablement combined, as a single function, to anticipate challenges of the revenue organization and uses, monitors, modifies, and deploys the information, tools, and processes necessary to successfully address those challenges</dd>
</dl>

<p>Many businesses operate with GTM/sales/revenue operations and enablement as separate functional areas; the ops leader reporting into someone and the enablement leader reporting into someone else. This is a mistake, a holdover from the days of “sales admins” and “sales training.” Separation creates inefficiencies within their respective teams, as well as unnecessary complexity for the field. As both operations and enablement exist to drive revenue growth, they should be woven together to drive a unified, strategic cadence of programs, both novel and routine, to the field.</p>

<p>The implications are huge. Let’s explore them.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="revenue_success" /><category term="revenue_success" /><category term="sales" /><category term="revenue" /><category term="gtm" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[It is time to start thinking about revenue operations and revenue enablement as a single function. I propose that revenue success is a function akin to customer success. Hubspot’s defines customer success, in part, as a business function that “[anticipates] customer challenges or questions and proactively providing solutions and answers.” Therefore, I suggest a working definition of revenue success:]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">A Little Break</title><link href="https://www.rejniak.com/admin/2023/04/28/a_little_break.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A Little Break" /><published>2023-04-28T01:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2023-04-28T01:00:00-07:00</updated><id>https://www.rejniak.com/admin/2023/04/28/a_little_break</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.rejniak.com/admin/2023/04/28/a_little_break.html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="taking-a-breather">Taking a breather</h2>

<p>Just in case someone is coming here to check me out as I’m starting to have conversations around my next gig, know that I have not deserted this site, nor have I given up on the Qualified Sales Leader ops/enablement companion reader project. I’m just taking some time for my own head. I finished my school program while I lost my mother. I need a little time to breathe. I’ll come back to this.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="admin" /><category term="personal" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Taking a breather]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">QSL: Chapter 1</title><link href="https://www.rejniak.com/qsl_for_revsuccess/2023/03/22/qsl-chapter-1.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="QSL: Chapter 1" /><published>2023-03-22T01:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2023-03-22T01:00:00-07:00</updated><id>https://www.rejniak.com/qsl_for_revsuccess/2023/03/22/qsl-chapter-1</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.rejniak.com/qsl_for_revsuccess/2023/03/22/qsl-chapter-1.html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="operations-and-enablement-reflections-on-the-qualified-sales-leader">Operations and Enablement Reflections on <em>The Qualified Sales Leader</em></h1>
<h2 id="chapter-1-introduction">Chapter 1: Introduction</h2>

<p>At first glance, one could argue that McMahon should have called The Qualified Sales Leader’s opening chapter The QBR. However, Introduction is quite right: The quarterly business review is indeed the perfect <em>introduction</em> to the sales and leadership challenges that McMahon explores for the reader throughout the book’s subsequent chapters.</p>

<p>It was in this first chapter where I asked myself, “Where’s ops? Where’s enablement?” Setting up the meeting environment, we read that, in addition to the author’s presence as a consultant, the CEO, the CRO, sales leaders, and reps are present in the room, but no mention of ops or enablement players. Fair enough, it’s not the focus of the book. I suspect, that in McMahon’s real world, there’s ops and enablement folks present. In my experience, I’ve seen plenty of QBRs go down just like that, with no ops and enablement participants. It’s a mistake. So, here we are.</p>

<p>Ops/enablement lesson number one. Be present in the QBR–emphasis on “be present.” Don’t just attend. Listen deeply and actively. Participate. You are a critically important participant in this event. More than likely, you and your team participated in preparing for the QBR. Use this event as a feedback loop to your work. Which artifacts, i.e., data, charts, analysis, were impactful and which ones were wasted effort? What questions couldn’t be readily answered? Were they the result of something missing from the artifacts or tools? Or, were the they simply from a lack of preparation? For those unanswered questions, were they meaningful, actionable, and insightful to the deal in question? Actively identify the gaps in sales process understanding and application. Ask your own clarifying questions that test whether or not everyone understands the meaning of the trade language, the lingo, in the same way. Look at the relationship dynamics between leaders, managers, and reps.</p>

<p>If you’re watching a series of “stump the chump” episodes, something is broken in the QBR process. McMahon describes a proper QBR as a learning and coaching session. It should be an event where reps can learn from the experience in the room, from their peers and their leaders. It should also deliver on an accurate view on the deal priorities in the quarter ahead so that action can be taken to both course correct and drive to a successful outcome. The same applies to ops and enablement leaders. This is an event to learn from your peers and your most important stakeholders. It’s an opportunity to identify gaps in learning, tools, and processes.</p>

<p>Consider the following action items:</p>
<ul>
  <li>Institute a required pre-read for all presenting reps to allow for preparation. Like any meeting, the best ones are the ones in which everyone comes prepared. The pre-read need not be exhaustive. In fact, I’d argue for the contrary. Instead presenters can focus on the facts scaffolded by your flavor of MEDDICC with the necessary deals that “walk” to their number. As we’ll explore later, most of this should be able to come out of your CRM.</li>
  <li>After the meeting, deliver a readout to your revenue leaders. This is your analysis and insights into what worked, what didn’t, and what prioritized ops and enablement opportunities you’re taking away for action this quarter. These shouldn’t derail your strategic ops and enablement roadmaps (you do have your strategically-aligned roadmap, right?), but rather initiatives and tasks that you can accomplish ahead of and to impact the next QBR.</li>
</ul>

<p>Of course, this is just an introduction. There’s a ton of details and lessons within The Qualified Sales Leader to reencode for ops and enablement leaders that culminate into your own QBR performance. In the upcoming 56 chapters, just like McMahon transforms the sales characters of his book, we’ll unpack his lessons to align you to your sales leadership and equip you as an ops and enablement leader to fully participate in the QBR–and beyond.</p>

<p>An aside.
Many businesses look at GTM/sales/revenue operations and enablement as separate functional areas; the ops leader reporting into someone and the enablement leader reporting into someone else. This is a mistake. I propose that the functions need to be considered a singular function within which both have their specialized, respective focus. I propose that we start to think about Revenue Success, akin to Customer Success. In the installments that follow, rather than refer to “ops and enablement,” I will simply refer to “rev success.”</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="qsl_for_revsuccess" /><category term="revenue_success" /><category term="sales" /><category term="revenue" /><category term="gtm" /><category term="qsl" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Operations and Enablement Reflections on The Qualified Sales Leader Chapter 1: Introduction]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">QSL: Chapter 2</title><link href="https://www.rejniak.com/qsl_for_revsuccess/2023/03/22/qsl-chapter-2.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="QSL: Chapter 2" /><published>2023-03-22T01:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2023-03-22T01:00:00-07:00</updated><id>https://www.rejniak.com/qsl_for_revsuccess/2023/03/22/qsl-chapter-2</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.rejniak.com/qsl_for_revsuccess/2023/03/22/qsl-chapter-2.html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="operations-and-enablement-reflections-on-the-qualified-sales-leader">Operations and Enablement Reflections on <em>The Qualified Sales Leader</em></h1>
<h2 id="chapter-2-introduction">Chapter 2: Introduction</h2>

<p>Coming soon.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="qsl_for_revsuccess" /><category term="revenue_success" /><category term="sales" /><category term="revenue" /><category term="gtm" /><category term="qsl" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Operations and Enablement Reflections on The Qualified Sales Leader Chapter 2: Introduction]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">QSL: Getting Started</title><link href="https://www.rejniak.com/qsl_for_revsuccess/2023/01/07/qsl-getting-started.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="QSL: Getting Started" /><published>2023-01-07T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2023-01-07T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>https://www.rejniak.com/qsl_for_revsuccess/2023/01/07/qsl-getting-started</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.rejniak.com/qsl_for_revsuccess/2023/01/07/qsl-getting-started.html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="operations-and-enablement-reflections-on-the-qualified-sales-leader">Operations and Enablement Reflections on <em>The Qualified Sales Leader</em></h1>

<h2 id="getting-started">Getting Started</h2>
<p>I won’t rehash <a href="https://www.google.com/search?q=qualified+sales+leader+summary">overviews</a> or <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Qualified-Sales-Leader-Proven-Lessons/dp/0578895064#customerReviews">reviews</a> of the <em>The Qualified Sales Leader</em> (QSL). Rather, allow me to introduce the this project and its objectives.</p>

<h4 id="about-me">About me</h4>
<p>As I’m writing this, I have about 15 years of experience as enterprise SaaS sales operations and enablement leader. I know how</p>

<h4 id="the-project">The Project</h4>
<p>Dvelop operations and enablement</p>

<p>Success criteria</p>

<h4 id="you">You</h4>
<p>Your feedback</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="qsl_for_revsuccess" /><category term="revenue_success" /><category term="sales" /><category term="revenue" /><category term="gtm" /><category term="qsl" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Operations and Enablement Reflections on The Qualified Sales Leader]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Some Writing Poject Ideas</title><link href="https://www.rejniak.com/admin/2023/01/04/some-ideas.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Some Writing Poject Ideas" /><published>2023-01-04T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2023-01-04T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>https://www.rejniak.com/admin/2023/01/04/some-ideas</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.rejniak.com/admin/2023/01/04/some-ideas.html"><![CDATA[<p>I’m sharing a couple of project ideas in the vein of “accountability” as I work on getting the wiring hooked up for production.</p>

<h3 id="an-operators-companion-to-the-qualified-sales-leader">An Operator’s Companion to The Qualified Sales Leader</h3>
<p><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/johnmcmahon1/">John McMahon’s</a> recent hit <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Qualified-Sales-Leader-Proven-Lessons/dp/0578895064"><em>The Qualified Sales Leader: Proven Lessons From a Five-Time CRO</em></a> codifies the seller and sales leader wisdom he developed while serving as CRO at PTC, Geo-Tel, Ariba, BladeLogic, and BMC. The book illuminates the perils and pearls of a modern-day, enterprise-software seller, from QBR to Closed.</p>

<p>I will provide a chapter-by-chapter interpretration of <em>The Qualified Sales Leader</em> from an operations and enablement perspective. I’ll attempt to create an operator’s companion to help the massive operations and enablement community to better align with and support the field’s motion.</p>

<p>With 57 chapters across five parts, I’m thinking:</p>
<ul>
  <li>Reflect on two chapters a week (occassionally more; some chapters are a page or two)</li>
  <li>Post the content on LinkedIn in hopes of generating discussion and feedback</li>
  <li>Complete in about six months (in parallel with work and last term of school)</li>
  <li>Edit and compile version one a month or so later</li>
</ul>

<h3 id="diary-of-an-internet-sensation">Diary of an Internet Sensation</h3>
<p>Through the process of helping my mother navigate a family-motivated legal dispute a few years ago, I learned that one of my cousins published many, in my opinion, despicable articles about other close family members—but then I learned there were many years worth of his online and courtroom battles. I was fascinated by the bombastic writings, the different personas, the contradictions, the bravado, the inhumanity.</p>

<p>I’m inspired to compile, connect, and catalog them here.</p>

<p>No plan here, yet. Rough ideas. This will require a lot of leg work. This will be me scratching an old journalism itch.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="admin" /><category term="ideas" /><category term="projects" /><category term="writing" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I’m sharing a couple of project ideas in the vein of “accountability” as I work on getting the wiring hooked up for production.]]></summary></entry></feed>