<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://www.rejniak.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://www.rejniak.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2023-07-15T13:24:59-07:00</updated><id>https://www.rejniak.com/feed.xml</id><title type="html">mick</title><subtitle>Exploring ideas at the intersection of data science and revenue operations &amp; enablement. Also space for personal obervations &amp; rants. </subtitle><entry><title type="html">Revenue Success &amp;amp; The QSL: Ch. 6</title><link href="https://www.rejniak.com/qsl_for_revsuccess/2023/07/14/qsl-chapter-6.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Revenue Success &amp;amp; The QSL: Ch. 6" /><published>2023-07-14T01:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2023-07-14T01:00:00-07:00</updated><id>https://www.rejniak.com/qsl_for_revsuccess/2023/07/14/qsl-chapter-6</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.rejniak.com/qsl_for_revsuccess/2023/07/14/qsl-chapter-6.html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="/qsl_for_revsuccess/2023/06/20/qsl-chapter-5.html">Previous Chapter</a> | Next Chapter coming soon …</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>Aside: A thought on this project’s format
At this point, I realize what I really want to do with this project. I want to create a revenue success and data playbook—something I can walk into a business with and get to work. To that end, I need to surface the “plays.” Don’t bury the lede as we say. I’ve added “The plays” section right after the name and quick synopsis of the chapter for orientation to call out the actionable bits I’m pulling from the chapter for revsuccess operators. “Notes” follow. Hell, a couple actions per chapter will potentially net us over a hundred actions to move our orgs forward. Worth it. When it’s all over, I’ll pull all the plays into a single post. Fun.</p>

  <p>On to the working format …</p>
</blockquote>

<h3 id="same-scenario-different-rep">Same Scenario, Different Rep</h3>
<p>With the QBR setup complete, McMahon provides the summation of a busted forecasting process from McMahon. He lays out what I think are the key, core issues at play and that will be worked through in the remainder of the book. Of course we’ll also learn about and work through adjacent and enabling dysfunctions along the way.</p>

<h4 id="the-plays">The plays</h4>
<ol>
  <li><strong>Create a glossary.</strong> Write down the definitions of key terms that are used in revenue conversations. These are the words that are used between sales, channels, marketing, and customer leaders and their teams as well as the CEO, CFO, and the board. Define ARR, bookings, one-time, MQL, SQL, your stages, deal reg, products, churn risk—literally all of it, any word you wouldn’t use at home or in your Tinder profile, make sure the defition is written down. Start a Google Doc or whatever collaborative writing tool you’re using and make sure everyone has access to it. Acknowledge that it’s a working doc, and depending on the your org’s stage of maturity, subject to change. (With increasing maturity, changes will be subject to increasing  governance.) Better yet, compile your definitions in an <a href="https://observablehq.com">Observable</a> notebook. This can ensure that the data team can more easily surface definitions in their dashboards and reports, either as links or cue cards. Here’s a <a href="/data_science/2023/06/20/observable.html">couple thoughts</a> on why you should be using Observable.</li>
  <li><strong>Develop inspection templates.</strong> Develop templates for reviewing any cyclical pieces of the business. The obvious one here is opportunity review, but there’s the campaigns/demand gen, pipeline, territories/accounts, customers/renewals, channel partners. Make sure these templates autopopulate with relevant metrics and data that will support conversations with insights. Make sure that these templates align directly to the agreed upon customer journey and how you quantify and qualify the health of these components. There are A LOT of tools to support reviewing these components of the business; anything that was a spreadsheet now has a SaaS replacement. But the most important piece is that there’s an alignment between the tooling and how you measure a comnponent’s health. With the book and the rest of this project, it will be all about MEDDPICC and opportunities, for example.</li>
</ol>

<h4 id="notes">Notes</h4>
<p>The two great failures of a sales org surface in the QBR: language and inspection. Neither the reps nor managers are using the same meanings of the words they use to describe deals. What’s meant by champion? By pain? By decision-maker? Lack of shared, aligned language undermines the shared, accurate state of a deal, of all deals. Qualification in this context does not the one-time qualification of whether or not it’s an opporunity. Qualification means the ever-changing state of the opportunity as deal dynamics unfold. One of my other favorite sales axioms: A deal’s not done until it’s done. Until it’s done, it’s constantly being qualified. With shitty qualification comes a shitty forecast, because the forecast is just the sum of the qualified deals–especially when you think of that qualification as weighting. Even if that deal is well prosecuted and qualified, without the shared language no one else really knows–and enterprise SaaS selling is a team sport</p>

<p>Managers and leaders don’t inspect in a consistent effective way. McMahon tells of manager inquiry intensity, as well as rep anxiety, waning throughout the QBR. Starts out hot, yields little, and starts to falter. This is the result of incoherent inspection, i.e., how are the questions asked linked to what they’re really looking to understand, namely how much is closing and if it’s not closing, how can it? Coherent inspection will illuminate the path, or lack thereof, to closing. That path may very well look like a map out of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pitfall!">Pitfall</a> with snakes, quicksand, and bottomless pits. But if you can see it, you can navigate it. Or bail—nothing is worse than putting time and effort on a deal that’s never going to happen.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="qsl_for_revsuccess" /><category term="revenue_success" /><category term="sales" /><category term="revenue" /><category term="gtm" /><category term="qsl" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Previous Chapter | Next Chapter coming soon …]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Observable</title><link href="https://www.rejniak.com/data_science/2023/06/20/observable.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Observable" /><published>2023-06-20T01:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2023-06-20T01:00:00-07:00</updated><id>https://www.rejniak.com/data_science/2023/06/20/observable</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.rejniak.com/data_science/2023/06/20/observable.html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://observablehq.com/">Observable</a> is the future of visualization. It revolves around JavaScript for wrangling data and drawing charts so you can use popular visualization JS libraries like <a href="https://d3js.org/">D3</a> and <a href="https://github.com/vega/vega">Vega</a>, but their own <a href="https://observablehq.com/plot/">Plot</a> library is a powerful and easy-to-use toolset for most day-to-day viz needs. It uses the notebook paradigm—which is great for anyone familiar with Jupyter, Colab—allowing Markdown documentation and Javascript to live together; great for sharing, collaboration, and iteration.</p>

<p>A little example of a plot I made in a tutorial usign Plot earlier today–embedded directly from my notebook. I met Obsrvable during my time in MIDS, but I’m falling in love with it all over again.</p>

<iframe width="100%" height="590.703125" frameborder="0" src="https://observablehq.com/embed/c005a90183eb51fa@996?cells=toyChart"></iframe>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="data_science" /><category term="visualization" /><category term="data" /><category term="metrics" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Observable is the future of visualization. It revolves around JavaScript for wrangling data and drawing charts so you can use popular visualization JS libraries like D3 and Vega, but their own Plot library is a powerful and easy-to-use toolset for most day-to-day viz needs. It uses the notebook paradigm—which is great for anyone familiar with Jupyter, Colab—allowing Markdown documentation and Javascript to live together; great for sharing, collaboration, and iteration.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Revenue Success &amp;amp; The QSL: Ch. 4</title><link href="https://www.rejniak.com/qsl_for_revsuccess/2023/06/20/qsl-chapter-4.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Revenue Success &amp;amp; The QSL: Ch. 4" /><published>2023-06-20T01:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2023-06-20T01:00:00-07:00</updated><id>https://www.rejniak.com/qsl_for_revsuccess/2023/06/20/qsl-chapter-4</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.rejniak.com/qsl_for_revsuccess/2023/06/20/qsl-chapter-4.html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="/qsl_for_revsuccess/2023/05/25/qsl-chapter-3.html">Previous Chapter</a> | <a href="/qsl_for_revsuccess/2023/06/20/qsl-chapter-5.html">Next Chapter</a></p>

<h3 id="kathleen">Kathleen</h3>

<p>Next rep, Kathleen. Second to the last, by the way. The big takeaway here is that Kathleen’s forecast introduces some tension between her manager and another manager. The other manager is frustrated by her manager not holding her accountable. Bad qualifying leads to bad forecasting leads to bad management leads to bad morale.</p>

<p>She’s the quintessential competitive rep. She forecasts over quota and says the things that the leaders want to hear which, in turn, secures an easier interrogation of her deals. She tells ‘em what they want to hear, and they have happy ears. She also forecasts a deal for the third time at a reduced amount for the third time which leads the author to inject my favorite deal quotes:</p>
<blockquote>
  <p>Time kills deals.</p>

  <p>All bad deals die a slow death.</p>
</blockquote>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="qsl_for_revsuccess" /><category term="revenue_success" /><category term="sales" /><category term="revenue" /><category term="gtm" /><category term="qsl" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Previous Chapter | Next Chapter]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Revenue Success &amp;amp; The QSL: Ch. 5</title><link href="https://www.rejniak.com/qsl_for_revsuccess/2023/06/20/qsl-chapter-5.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Revenue Success &amp;amp; The QSL: Ch. 5" /><published>2023-06-20T01:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2023-06-20T01:00:00-07:00</updated><id>https://www.rejniak.com/qsl_for_revsuccess/2023/06/20/qsl-chapter-5</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.rejniak.com/qsl_for_revsuccess/2023/06/20/qsl-chapter-5.html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="/qsl_for_revsuccess/2023/06/20/qsl-chapter-4.html">Previous Chapter</a> | <a href="/qsl_for_revsuccess/2023/07/14/qsl-chapter-6.html">Next Chapter</a></p>

<h3 id="hannlin">Hannlin</h3>

<p>Last rep in this QBR setup. We’re getting there. The aha from this rep’s deals detail is that they don’t control their POC process. They don’t know the success criteria or when the POC is completed.</p>

<p>Hannlin is the hyper-confident, hyper-active rep. Lots of activity, responding to RFPs, running POCs, but no control. Like the rep before him, he forecasts over quota. Also like the rep before him, there’s tension between Hannlin’s manager and the other manager who resents slipped deals being in the forecast and the lack of accountability for reps.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="qsl_for_revsuccess" /><category term="revenue_success" /><category term="sales" /><category term="revenue" /><category term="gtm" /><category term="qsl" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Previous Chapter | Next Chapter]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Revenue Success &amp;amp; The QSL: Ch. 2</title><link href="https://www.rejniak.com/qsl_for_revsuccess/2023/05/25/qsl-chapter-2.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Revenue Success &amp;amp; The QSL: Ch. 2" /><published>2023-05-25T01:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2023-05-25T01:00:00-07:00</updated><id>https://www.rejniak.com/qsl_for_revsuccess/2023/05/25/qsl-chapter-2</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.rejniak.com/qsl_for_revsuccess/2023/05/25/qsl-chapter-2.html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="/qsl_for_revsuccess/2023/03/22/qsl-chapter-1.html">Previous Chapter</a> | <a href="/qsl_for_revsuccess/2023/05/25/qsl-chapter-3.html">Next Chapter</a></p>

<h3 id="shannon">Shannon</h3>

<p>McMahon uses this, and the next few chapters, to personify what’s wrong with deal qualification and inspection. He continues with the QBR as the setting to develop his characters who tell the story of how enterprise software sales is screwed up. You have to read the book to appreciate the pyscho-emotional landscape of a business review that McMahon conveys so well. For our purposes, we’re looking for ops and enablement data lessons.</p>

<p>First up is Shannon. She presents some of her deals in forecast that managers and leaders in the room ask questions while the author interjects commentary that highlights the brokenness of the process. We’re introduced to the concepts and terms that become the substance of the book later, like Champion and Coach, process and stages. The text portrays a typical deal review with managers and leaders asking a bevy of ad-hoc, reactive, and–what McMahon calls–“superficial” questions that receive mostly unsatisying answers. The review ends with the rep, Shannon, calling a forecast amount just below her quota “with a shot at” full quota. McMahon makes it clear that there’s nothing substantive about her forecast.</p>

<p>Classic.</p>

<p>Although the book uses a quarterly business review as the setting, some of us have lived this nightmare every week.</p>

<p>Again, the book is setting up context and working to adequately illustrate the problem. We won’t get too far into solutioning for revenue success and data just yet. But in the spirit of motivating solutions, let’s call out the obvious problems:</p>
<ul>
  <li>Inaccuracy. There’s nothing to support the forecasted amount.</li>
  <li>Inefficiency. Even if it was accurate, there’s way too many words exchanged, time and energy consumed, to get to the simple, object of desire: the forecast.</li>
</ul>

<p>And here were are. Inefficient inaccuracy is the epitome of waste in a business process. Measuring variance and error in predictions is bread-and-butter to data science. McMahon proposes a way to fix all this, and we’ll look at ways to support those fixes because process and data exist at the core of revenue success.</p>

<p>Before we move on to the upcoming chapters where we meet Carlos, Kathleen, and Hannlin, I think it’s worth the one big lesson from Shannon’s time at the podium:</p>
<ul>
  <li>Consistent format with a minimum expectation of completeness. The deal details should be presented in consistent way. Certain data points should be required. As we work through the book, we’ll fill in what those details should be. This could be a preso template, preferably something that can be generated from CRM details so that reps are not having to type anything twice. But, of course this would mean that the information is already in the CRM.</li>
</ul>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="qsl_for_revsuccess" /><category term="revenue_success" /><category term="sales" /><category term="revenue" /><category term="gtm" /><category term="qsl" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Previous Chapter | Next Chapter]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Revenue Success &amp;amp; The QSL: Ch. 3</title><link href="https://www.rejniak.com/qsl_for_revsuccess/2023/05/25/qsl-chapter-3.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Revenue Success &amp;amp; The QSL: Ch. 3" /><published>2023-05-25T01:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2023-05-25T01:00:00-07:00</updated><id>https://www.rejniak.com/qsl_for_revsuccess/2023/05/25/qsl-chapter-3</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.rejniak.com/qsl_for_revsuccess/2023/05/25/qsl-chapter-3.html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="/qsl_for_revsuccess/2023/05/25/qsl-chapter-2.html">Previous Chapter</a> | <a href="/qsl_for_revsuccess/2023/06/20/qsl-chapter-4.html">Next Chapter</a></p>

<h3 id="carlos">Carlos</h3>

<p>OK, stay with me here. We’re still in the QBR. This is like a sales soap opera episode. Carlos is the rep presenting. With this character the book introduces us to a glimpse of what “good” could look like as a seller forecasting their number. “This was one rep I admired,” McMahon writes. He is firm in what he is forecasting although it is well below the quota and the managers put on pressure for him to increase it. He knows where his deals stand and where some of his blind spots are.</p>

<p>The lesson of this chapter is sandbagging, when reps commit to a lower number than they have high confidence that they can deliver, i.e., promise low, deliver high. But more often, they’re compelled to forecast high and end up dropping the commit at the end of the quarter. This serves no one well, except maybe the sales leader. Like a warm bed on a cold morning, you know you have to face it, but you put off the discomfort as long as you can.</p>

<p>Rev success data lessons? How does Carlos know more about his deals than Shannon? And how do we make sure what Carlos knows is captured consistently so that all the reps have the same confidence in their forecast?</p>

<p>The problem here is consistency and alignment. There’s no consistent qualification understanding between two reps. There’s no alignment between rep and manager. There’s no agreement on how to call balls and strikes. There’s just guts and bias and prejudice.</p>

<p>Again, this is the just the setup. Answers come, but for now, let’s just appreciate the questions and what the problem looks like. We’ve got, like, 54 more chapters to get through. 😜</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="qsl_for_revsuccess" /><category term="revenue_success" /><category term="sales" /><category term="revenue" /><category term="gtm" /><category term="qsl" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Previous Chapter | Next Chapter]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Revenue Success</title><link href="https://www.rejniak.com/revenue_success/2023/05/08/revenue_success.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Revenue Success" /><published>2023-05-08T01:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2023-05-08T01:00:00-07:00</updated><id>https://www.rejniak.com/revenue_success/2023/05/08/revenue_success</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.rejniak.com/revenue_success/2023/05/08/revenue_success.html"><![CDATA[<p>It is time to start thinking about revenue operations and revenue enablement as a single function. I propose that <em>revenue success</em> is a function akin to <em>customer success</em>. Hubspot’s <a href="https://blog.hubspot.com/service/customer-success">defines customer success</a>, in part, as a business function that “[anticipates] customer challenges or questions and proactively providing solutions and answers.” Therefore, I suggest a working definition of revenue success:</p>

<dl>
  <dt>Revenue success</dt>
  <dd>Revenue operations and revenue enablement combined, as a single function, to anticipate challenges of the revenue organization and uses, monitors, modifies, and deploys the information, tools, and processes necessary to successfully address those challenges</dd>
</dl>

<p>Many businesses operate with GTM/sales/revenue operations and enablement as separate functional areas; the ops leader reporting into someone and the enablement leader reporting into someone else. This is a mistake, a holdover from the days of “sales admins” and “sales training.” Separation creates inefficiencies within their respective teams, as well as unnecessary complexity for the field. As both operations and enablement exist to drive revenue growth, they should be woven together to drive a unified, strategic cadence of programs, both novel and routine, to the field.</p>

<p>The implications are huge. Let’s explore them.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="revenue_success" /><category term="revenue_success" /><category term="sales" /><category term="revenue" /><category term="gtm" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[It is time to start thinking about revenue operations and revenue enablement as a single function. I propose that revenue success is a function akin to customer success. Hubspot’s defines customer success, in part, as a business function that “[anticipates] customer challenges or questions and proactively providing solutions and answers.” Therefore, I suggest a working definition of revenue success:]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">A Little Break</title><link href="https://www.rejniak.com/admin/2023/04/28/a_little_break.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A Little Break" /><published>2023-04-28T01:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2023-04-28T01:00:00-07:00</updated><id>https://www.rejniak.com/admin/2023/04/28/a_little_break</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.rejniak.com/admin/2023/04/28/a_little_break.html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="taking-a-breather">Taking a breather</h2>

<p>Just in case someone is coming here to check me out as I’m starting to have conversations around my next gig, know that I have not deserted this site, nor have I given up on the Qualified Sales Leader ops/enablement companion reader project. I’m just taking some time for my own head. I finished my school program while I lost my mother. I need a little time to breathe. I’ll come back to this.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="admin" /><category term="personal" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Taking a breather]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Revenue Success &amp;amp; The QSL: Ch. 1</title><link href="https://www.rejniak.com/qsl_for_revsuccess/2023/03/22/qsl-chapter-1.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Revenue Success &amp;amp; The QSL: Ch. 1" /><published>2023-03-22T01:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2023-03-22T01:00:00-07:00</updated><id>https://www.rejniak.com/qsl_for_revsuccess/2023/03/22/qsl-chapter-1</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.rejniak.com/qsl_for_revsuccess/2023/03/22/qsl-chapter-1.html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="/qsl_for_revsuccess/2023/01/07/qsl-getting-started.html">Getting Started</a> | <a href="/qsl_for_revsuccess/2023/05/25/qsl-chapter-2.html">Next Chapter</a></p>

<h3 id="introduction">Introduction</h3>

<p>At first glance, one could argue that McMahon should have called The Qualified Sales Leader’s opening chapter The QBR. However, “Introduction” is quite right: The quarterly business review is indeed the perfect <em>introduction</em> to the sales and leadership challenges that McMahon explores for the reader throughout the book’s subsequent chapters.</p>

<p>It was in this first chapter where I asked myself, “Where’s ops? Where’s enablement? What’s the data?” Setting up the meeting environment, we read that, in addition to the author’s presence as a consultant, the CEO, the CRO, sales leaders, and reps are present in the room, but no mention of ops or enablement players. Fair enough, it’s not the focus of the book. I suspect, that in McMahon’s real world, there’s ops and enablement folks present. However, in my experience, I’ve seen plenty of QBRs go down just like that, with no ops and enablement participants. It’s a mistake. So, here we are.</p>

<p>Ops/enablement lesson number one. Be present in the QBR–emphasis on “be present.” Don’t just attend. Listen deeply and actively. Participate. You are a critically important participant in this event. More than likely, you and your team participated in preparing for the QBR. Use this event as a feedback loop to your work. Which artifacts, i.e., data, charts, analysis, were impactful and which ones were wasted effort? What questions couldn’t be readily answered? Were they the result of something missing from the artifacts or tools? Or, were the they simply from a lack of preparation? For those unanswered questions, were they meaningful, actionable, and insightful to the deal in question? Actively identify the gaps in sales process understanding and application. Ask your own clarifying questions that test whether or not everyone understands the meaning of the trade language, the lingo, in the same way. Look at the relationship dynamics between leaders, managers, and reps.</p>

<p>If you’re watching a series of “stump the chump” episodes, something is broken in the QBR process. McMahon describes a proper QBR as a learning and coaching session. It should be an event where reps can learn from the experience in the room, from their peers and their leaders. It should also deliver on an accurate view on the deal priorities in the quarter ahead so that action can be taken to both course correct and drive to a successful outcome. The same applies to ops and enablement leaders. This is an event to learn from your peers and your most important stakeholders. It’s an opportunity to identify gaps in learning, tools, and processes.</p>

<p>Consider the following action items:</p>
<ul>
  <li>Institute a required pre-read for all presenting reps to allow for preparation. Like any meeting, the best ones are the ones in which everyone comes prepared. The pre-read need not be exhaustive. In fact, I’d argue for the contrary. Instead presenters can focus on the facts scaffolded by your flavor of MEDDICC with the necessary deals that “walk” to their number. As we’ll explore later, most of this should be able to come out of your CRM.</li>
  <li>After the meeting, deliver a readout to your revenue leaders. This is your analysis and insights into what worked, what didn’t, and what prioritized ops and enablement opportunities you’re taking away for action this quarter. These shouldn’t derail your strategic ops and enablement roadmaps (you do have your strategically-aligned roadmap, right?), but rather initiatives and tasks that you can accomplish ahead of and to impact the next QBR.</li>
</ul>

<p>Of course, this is just an introduction. There’s a ton of details and lessons within The Qualified Sales Leader to reencode for ops and enablement leaders that culminate into your own QBR performance. In the upcoming 56 chapters, just like McMahon transforms the sales characters of his book, we’ll unpack his lessons to align you to your sales leadership and equip you as an ops and enablement leader to fully participate in the QBR–and beyond.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="qsl_for_revsuccess" /><category term="revenue_success" /><category term="sales" /><category term="revenue" /><category term="gtm" /><category term="qsl" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Getting Started | Next Chapter]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Revenue Success &amp;amp; The QSL: Getting Started</title><link href="https://www.rejniak.com/qsl_for_revsuccess/2023/01/07/qsl-getting-started.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Revenue Success &amp;amp; The QSL: Getting Started" /><published>2023-01-07T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2023-01-07T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>https://www.rejniak.com/qsl_for_revsuccess/2023/01/07/qsl-getting-started</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.rejniak.com/qsl_for_revsuccess/2023/01/07/qsl-getting-started.html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="operations-and-enablement-reflections-on-the-qualified-sales-leader">Operations and Enablement Reflections on <em>The Qualified Sales Leader</em></h2>

<h3 id="tldr">tl;dr</h3>
<p>Let’s build a revenue success (operations and enablement) data playbook based on <em>The Qualified Sales Leader</em>.</p>

<h3 id="getting-started">Getting Started</h3>
<p><em>The Qualified Sales Leader</em> (QSL) by John McMahon provides an education on motivating sales success through a ton of colorful, pointed anecdotes to deliver wisdom and “lessons from a five time CRO.” Although the book is focused on managers and leaders, it is, of course, a valuable read for the individual contributor as well as the operations and enablement practitioner. I won’t rehash <a href="https://www.google.com/search?q=qualified+sales+leader+summary">overviews</a> or <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Qualified-Sales-Leader-Proven-Lessons/dp/0578895064#customerReviews">reviews</a> of the QSL. Rather, allow me to introduce the this project and its objectives.</p>

<p>The QSL is the sales manual of our time.</p>

<h4 id="the-project">The Project</h4>
<p>As the the focus of the book is on creating successful software sales teams, I would argue that at the very core of that success–and, really, at the heart of the QSL–is a specialized alignment from CEO to rep, and with every role in between, on process and language. I would further argue that in the real world execution of those processes and implementation of that language, that operations and enablement is key to scale of any size. Finally, I argue that the most critical element of an effective operations and enablement organization is data.</p>

<p>(I should add an aside re: the importance of data in ops and enablement, with a main theme about adaptation, evolution through data …)</p>

<p>Therefore, this project will identify ways for operations and enablement teams to support a qualified sales organization, especially where data plays a key role. We will work through the QSL chapter-by-chapter unpacking the lessons from the book for actionable insights and tactics that operations and enablement leaders and practitioners can use to help their sales organizations grow.</p>

<p>An aside.
I propose that the operations and enablement functions need to be considered a singular function. I propose that we start to think about <a href="/revenue_success/2023/05/08/revenue_success.html">Revenue Success</a>. In the installments that follow, rather than refer to “ops and enablement,” I will simply refer to “rev success.”</p>

<h5 id="you">You</h5>
<p>I’m simply working to add to the discourse to improve selling. Of course, like any idea, like the entire body of human knowledge, it’s a work in progress. And that progress needs your input. Please provide your feedback in the comments or send an email to mick@rejniak.com.</p>

<h5 id="about-me">About me</h5>
<p>I’m a GTM data scientist. As I’m writing this, I have about 15 years of experience as enterprise SaaS sales operations and enablement leader. Prior to that, I sold digital design services to large consumer entertainment brands, like Sony, Fox, and Comedy Central.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="qsl_for_revsuccess" /><category term="revenue_success" /><category term="sales" /><category term="revenue" /><category term="gtm" /><category term="qsl" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Operations and Enablement Reflections on The Qualified Sales Leader]]></summary></entry></feed>