<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2023-01-04T01:03:23-08:00</updated><id>/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Rejniak Dot Com</title><subtitle>Exploring ideas at the intersection of data science and revenue operations &amp; enablement. Also space for personal obervations &amp; rants. </subtitle><entry><title type="html">Some Writing Poject Ideas</title><link href="/admin/2023/01/04/some-ideas.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Some Writing Poject Ideas" /><published>2023-01-04T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2023-01-04T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>/admin/2023/01/04/some-ideas</id><content type="html" xml:base="/admin/2023/01/04/some-ideas.html"><![CDATA[<p>I’m sharing a couple of project ideas in the vein of “accountability” as I work on getting the wiring hooked up for production.</p>

<h3 id="an-operators-companion-to-the-qualified-sales-leader">An Operator’s Companion to The Qualified Sales Leader</h3>
<p><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/johnmcmahon1/">John McMahon’s</a> recent hit <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Qualified-Sales-Leader-Proven-Lessons/dp/0578895064"><em>The Qualified Sales Leader: Proven Lessons From a Five-Time CRO</em></a> codifies the seller and sales leader wisdom he developed while serving as CRO at PTC, Geo-Tel, Ariba, BladeLogic, and BMC. The book illuminates the perils and pearls of a modern day enterprise software seller, from QBR to close.</p>

<p>I will provide a chapter-by-chapter interpretration of <em>The Qualified Sales Leader</em> from an operations and enablement perspective. I’ll attempt to create an operator’s companion to help the massive operations and enablement community to align with</p>

<p>With 57 chapters across five parts, I’m thinking:</p>
<ul>
  <li>Reflect on two chapters a week (occassionally more; some chapters are a page or two)</li>
  <li>Post the content on LinkedIn in hopes of generating discussion and feedback</li>
  <li>Complete in about six months (in parallel with work and last term of school)</li>
  <li>Edit and compile version one a month or so later</li>
</ul>

<h3 id="diary-of-an-internet-sensation">Diary of an Internet Sensation</h3>
<p>Through the process of helping my mother navigate a family-motivated legal dispute a few years ago, I learned that one of my cousins published many, in my opinion, despicable articles about other close family members—but then I learned there were many years worth of his online and courtroom battles. I was fascinated by the bombastic writings, the different personas, the contradictions, the bravado, the inhumanity.</p>

<p>I’m inspired to compile, connect, and cataloge them here.</p>

<p>No plan here, yet. Rough ideas. This will require a lot of leg work. This will be me scratching an old journalism itch.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="admin" /><category term="ideas" /><category term="projects" /><category term="writing" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I’m sharing a couple of project ideas in the vein of “accountability” as I work on getting the wiring hooked up for production.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Welcome to Jekyll!</title><link href="/jekyll/update/2023/01/03/welcome-to-jekyll.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Welcome to Jekyll!" /><published>2023-01-03T17:56:59-08:00</published><updated>2023-01-03T17:56:59-08:00</updated><id>/jekyll/update/2023/01/03/welcome-to-jekyll</id><content type="html" xml:base="/jekyll/update/2023/01/03/welcome-to-jekyll.html"><![CDATA[<p>You’ll find this post in your <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">_posts</code> directory. Go ahead and edit it and re-build the site to see your changes. You can rebuild the site in many different ways, but the most common way is to run <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">jekyll serve</code>, which launches a web server and auto-regenerates your site when a file is updated.</p>

<p>Jekyll requires blog post files to be named according to the following format:</p>

<p><code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">YEAR-MONTH-DAY-title.MARKUP</code></p>

<p>Where <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">YEAR</code> is a four-digit number, <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">MONTH</code> and <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">DAY</code> are both two-digit numbers, and <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">MARKUP</code> is the file extension representing the format used in the file. After that, include the necessary front matter. Take a look at the source for this post to get an idea about how it works.</p>

<p>Jekyll also offers powerful support for code snippets:</p>

<figure class="highlight"><pre><code class="language-ruby" data-lang="ruby"><span class="k">def</span> <span class="nf">print_hi</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="nb">name</span><span class="p">)</span>
  <span class="nb">puts</span> <span class="s2">"Hi, </span><span class="si">#{</span><span class="nb">name</span><span class="si">}</span><span class="s2">"</span>
<span class="k">end</span>
<span class="n">print_hi</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="s1">'Tom'</span><span class="p">)</span>
<span class="c1">#=&gt; prints 'Hi, Tom' to STDOUT.</span></code></pre></figure>

<p>Check out the <a href="https://jekyllrb.com/docs/home">Jekyll docs</a> for more info on how to get the most out of Jekyll. File all bugs/feature requests at <a href="https://github.com/jekyll/jekyll">Jekyll’s GitHub repo</a>. If you have questions, you can ask them on <a href="https://talk.jekyllrb.com/">Jekyll Talk</a>.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="jekyll" /><category term="update" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[You’ll find this post in your _posts directory. Go ahead and edit it and re-build the site to see your changes. You can rebuild the site in many different ways, but the most common way is to run jekyll serve, which launches a web server and auto-regenerates your site when a file is updated.]]></summary></entry></feed>